<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fundamentals :: Current and historical information on the level of Lake Constance</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/index.html</link>
    <description>Fundamental elements of the analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/max_general/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/max_general/index.html</guid>
      <description>The maximum level This article collects some information about the maximum level of Lake Constance.&#xA;Hourly average as a basis. First of all, it is important to understand that the maximum in the LUBW representations is based on hourly averages. And for this website we decided to take the same approach - even if it complicates things. In fact, two types of data are mixed in the graph. The maximum is determined based on hourly average values for each day. However, the daily average is used for the mean, the error band and the minimum. My guess is that they want to satisfy local perceptions here. When people say that the maximum during the flood in 1999 was 565cm, then in such an overview you don’t want to work with the daily average, which was lower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/min_general/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/min_general/index.html</guid>
      <description>The minimum level This article collects some information about the maximum level of Lake Constance.&#xA;Daily average values as a basis. In contrast to the maximum, the minimum is determined based on daily average values. In my opinion, this is not entirely consistent. At this point we are following the LUBW approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis Period</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/time_frame/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/02_analysis/02_01_basics/time_frame/index.html</guid>
      <description>Defining the right analysis period Choosing the right analysis period 1817 / 1850 / 1888 / 1981 / 1983 If you look at graphics of the lake’s annual course, the course of the maximum varies considerably in some cases. This is due to different definitions of the analysis period for determining the long-term values. Here is an overview of the different approaches that I am currently aware of:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>