<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About :: Current and historical information on the level of Lake Constance</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/index.html</link>
    <description>And here you can find “About” information, such as the imprint, contact details, etc. And I also want to talk a little about the background of this website.&#xA;Why Technical Realization Release Notes Contact and Imprint Logo The most important information is:&#xA;Please Note All statements without guarantee.&#xA;I’m trying to build a reliable and helpful website here. But at the end of the day it’s a hobby. All information is therefore without guarantee.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:26:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/02_technical-realization/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/02_technical-realization/index.html</guid>
      <description>Implementation This website was built and is hosted on AWS. For all regional services, the eu-central-1 region was selected.&#xA;Lambda. We use lambda functions for two activities: 1/ scrape the data. 2/ process and visualize the data. The fictions are either triggered via EventsManager or as part of a StepFunction.&#xA;ECS. There functions used for data processing and visualization are relying on Python / Pandas. These libraries are too big for being added as zip (lambda limit is 125 MB). We therefore created docker containers for these functions same store them in ECS. We used Cloud9 to build the containers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/01_why/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/01_why/index.html</guid>
      <description>Why actually? This website is the result of a learning project. My real goal was to learn more about data analysis in general. I was looking for a suitable data set for this. And the level data for Lake Constance became available quite quickly. Since I grew up on Lake Constance, I have a connection to the data. The data itself is publicly accessible (#opendata). And the data set for the Konstanz measuring station is around 200 MB in size. This is a pretty ideal size, as you can no longer process this amount of data in Excel or other spreadsheet programs. But this is just tiny for analysis with Python / Pandas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/03_release-notes/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/03_release-notes/index.html</guid>
      <description>Release Notes 2024-12-20: Added 2024 longterm view to historic data. Added the longterm view for 2024 to the historical data.&#xA;2024-12-20: Full transition to API based data and Seaborn graphics. Complete transition to API data and updated graphics based on Seaborn.&#xA;2024-12-17: Update to JSON with API data. DE and EN transitioned to JSON based on API data. With that, we can provide new metrics (e.g. change last 24h).&#xA;2024-12-13: Transition to API and Seaborn for “current” graph. The graph showing the status of the last 10 days has been switched to API-based data (English version only for testing). This means that the data is now accurate to the millimeter. The graph has also been switched to Seaborn to achieve a more modern look.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact and Imprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/04_contact-imprint/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/04_contact-imprint/index.html</guid>
      <description>You can find more information about me on a separate blog: davidbeck.online&#xA;Contact For questions, comments, or ideas on how to improve this website, please reach out via email to pegel-konstanz.de.tribesman400@passmail.net . This is an email alias dedicated to this project.&#xA;Imprint This is a personal and non-commercial website from David Beck from Berlin, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/05_logo/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/en/03_about/05_logo/index.html</guid>
      <description>Our Logo At this point a few thoughts about the logo of our website.&#xA;Since it was about data analysis in Python right from the start, it seemed sensible to put together a logo using characters. There are no pretty pictures of Lake Constance on this website. There are already enough of them. It’s all about numbers - and the graphical representation of them.&#xA;And then of course there is the ups and downs of the lake. This resulted in the minimalist logo consisting of ^ and v.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>